Guide to the Yale in World War II Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale in World War II collection
1938-1946
MS 1212
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.5
(14 boxes)
The collection consists of printed matter, reports, correspondence, memoranda, radio scripts, memorabilia, scrapbooks and clippings documenting some of the activities at Yale University and of the individual colleges during World War II. Letters from Yale men in the services, both in the United States and abroad, to officials of the university make up a substantial part of the collection. Also included are correspondence and financial documents of the "Yale Library Project," a military intelligence operation secretly funded by the U.S. Office of Strategic Services which used Joseph T. Curtiss, a professor of English at Yale, as its agent.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was assembled from material collected from Yale Archives, research materials of Eugene H. Kone, and records of individual departments and institutes connected with Yale University. Gift of the New Haven Colony Historical Society, 2003.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series and one addition: I. Activities of Yale University. II. War Activities. III. Correspondence.
Scope and Contents
Yale in World War II brings together some of the surviving records and memorabilia of the activities on the Yale campus between 1939 and 1946. Other sources for records of this period include the Yale University Archives, the extensive research material (9 linear feet) collected by Eugene H. Kone for a projected book on Yale in World War II, and the records of individual departments and institutes connected with the university. This collection consists of printed matter, reports, correspondence, memoranda, radio scripts, scrapbooks and clippings concerning individuals and groups on the campus and overseas during World War II. Also included is a substantial amount of material on post-war planning. The papers consist of three series: I. Activities of Yale University, II. War Activities, III. Correspondence.
Series I., ACTIVITIES OF YALE UNIVERSITY, is divided into three sections: By Official Unit, By Topic, and Scrapbooks.
By Official Unit consists of the papers of official bodies of the university relating to their activities during the war. Of particular interest is a large amount of material issued between 1940 and 1942 by the Committee on Preparation for War Service and reports issued by the Institute of Human Relations and the Institute of International Studies during 1943 and 1944. A substantial correspondence between Bernhard Knollenberg, Yale University Librarian, and Herbert Hoover in 1940 concerning Hoover's plan to feed the population of the invaded countries in Europe is filed under "Yale University. Library." A small amount of material on Yale's Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children is also included in the section.
By Topic covers unofficial activities on the Yale campus and includes such areas as conscientious objectors, air raid precautions and relief organizations. Under the heading "Post-War Planning" are a number of reports written by the Yale University Post-War Planning Committee and various individuals between 1942 and 1945. Speakers at Yale, the texts of whose speeches are found here, include Earl Browder, secretary of the Communist Party of the United States, speaking under the auspices of the Yale Peace Council, Field Marshall John Dill of Great Britain (a reply by George C. Marshall is included), Charles A. Lindbergh, speaking under the auspices of the America First Committee, Henry R. Luce and Erika Mann. Also included in this section are memorabilia such as war ration books, savings bond literature and military passes required to enter military areas on the Old Campus.
Scrapbooks consists of three volumes of newspaper clippings from 1944 and 1945 which document achievements of Yale students and faculty, activities on the campus, and Yale's participation in the war.
Series II., WAR ACTIVITIES, is divided into three sections: On Campus, Abroad, and Articles, Reports, Clippings and Writings by Yale Men.
On Campus includes printed matter, reports and correspondence relating to the training programs on the Yale campus conducted by the various branches of the United States armed forces. The work of the Army Specialized Training Program and the Navy College Training Program, known as V-12, is documented through memoranda, curricula, course schedules and other printed matter.
Abroad consists of programs for various social functions of Yale men in the armed forces abroad.
Articles, Reports, Clippings and Writings by Yale Men documents the experiences of Yale men serving in the armed services.
Series III., CORRESPONDENCE, is made up of letters from former Yale students to Yale officials describing their experiences at military bases in the United States and while serving abroad. The Yale officials are James G. Leyburn, Acting Chairman, Dept. of Sociology, Carl A. Lohmann, Secretary of the University, Russell G. Pruden, Curator, Yale Collection of War Literature, Carl F. Schreiber, Chairman, Dept. of Germanic Languages, and Chauncey B. Tinker, Professor of English Literature. Miscellaneous correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Conscientious objectors; World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American; World War, 1939-1945 -- Secret service; World War, 1939-1945; Scrapbooks; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Aschmann, Charles George, 1919-; Bloom, Sol, 1870-1949; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973; Capper, Arthur, 1865-1951; Clarke, Samuel J.; Curtiss, Joseph T., 1901-1992; Dawson, Allan, 1913-; Dennis, Lawrence, 1893-1977; Dill, John; Donald, George Kenneth, 1890-; Forrestal, James, 1892-1949; Ginsburg, Harvey Hillson, 1922-; Haight, Gordon Sherman; Hammond, Lansing V. (Lansing Van der Heyden), 1906-; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986; Heymeyer, Alexander; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Kent, Sherman; Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1892-1973; Kunkel, John Crain, 1898-; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947; Lane, Arthur Bliss, 1894-1956; Leyburn, James Graham; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987; Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967; MacArthur, Douglas, 1909-; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Mahoney, John Edward, 1921-; Maloney, Francis Thomas, 1894-1945; Mann, Erika, 1905-1969; Mathias, Robert John, 1921-; Maurer, Oscar E. (Oscar Edward), 1878-; Mendenhall, Thomas C. (Thomas Corwin), 1910-1998; Nichols, George E.; O'Neal, Emmet, 1887-1967; Pforzheimer, Walter L. (Walter Lionel), 1914-2003; Preston, Austin Roe, 1894-1956; Pruden, Russell G.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944; Schreiber, Carl F. (Carl Frederick), 1886-1960; Sheppard, Morris, 1875-1941; Sizer, Theodore, 1892-1967; Smith, J. Joseph, 1904-; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Tittmann, Harold H., 1893-1980; Tuttle, H. E. (Henry Emerson), 1890-1946; Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1877-1952; Weddell, Alexander Wilbourne, 1876-1948; Wetherbee, Raymond, d.1945; Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall), 1882-1975; White, William Allen, 1868-1944; Williamson, Harold Long, 1891-; United States. Office of Strategic Services; Berkeley College (Yale University); Yale University -- History
- ACTIVITIES OF YALE UNIVERSITY, 1939-1946, undated; Series I; 3.25 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  By Official Unit is arranged alphabetically by official body of the university. By Topic is arranged alphabetically. Scrapbooks is arranged chronologically.
  - By Official Unit
    - Yale University. Alumni (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Alumni Board
        - Program for Yale Alumni Forum, 1940 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - An Introduction to Yale, galley proofs, 1945 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Yale Alumni University Fund Association/ Printed matter, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Lists of Yale alumni in the war, newspaper clippings, 1941-1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Yale Alumni War Service. Reports, printed matter, 1943, 1944 July 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yale University. Athletic Association/ Memoranda, 1942-1943, 1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale University. Berkeley College, 1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 5a)
      General
      See also: box 2, folder 39 See also: box 8, folder 112
    - Yale University. Board of Admissions/Applications, memoranda, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Yale University. Bureau of Military Information/ Memoranda, stationery, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Yale University. Committee on Preparation for War Service (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Memoranda, minutes, reports, 1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Student Preparation for War Service (pamphlet) - Drafts, correspondence, printed matter, 1942 March-July (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Curricula - Reports, drafts of reports, correspondence, 1942 February-Jul, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Educational and housing facilities (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Memoranda, reports, correspondence, 1942 September - Dec, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Report, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Interviews in Washington, D.C., 1942 May - September (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - General correspondence, 1942 April - 1943 January (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence - U.S. Army, 1942 January 20 - September 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence - U.S. Navy, 1942 January 27 - April 9 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence - U.S. Navy, 1942 April 10 - September 30 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Yale University. Committee on Selective Service (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Applications, memoranda, newspaper clippings, 1940 August - 1945 June (Box 2, Folder 18)
        General note
        See also: box 3, folder 41
    - Yale University. Corporation Statement, 1942 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Yale University. Dept. of Sociology Correspondence, 1941 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Yale University. Faculty (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Lists of faculty members concerning their participation in the war effort, 1942 Aug, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Questionnaire, 1942 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Yale University. Faculty. Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children/ Memoranda, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1940 June - September (Box 2, Folder 22)
      See also: box 1, folder 5a
    - Yale University. Institute of Human Relations (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - "Emergency Adaptations in Melanesia", 1943 January 11 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - "Food and Water in the Marshall Islands", 1943 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - "Gazeteer of the Marshall Islands", 1943 January 2 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Report of the Index of the Americas, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Yale University. Institute of International Studies Reports, 1944 March 15, 1944 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Yale University. Library
      - Kent, Sherman. "War Collection," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1940 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - [underline]. "Yale's Collection of War Literature," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1941 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Knollenberg, Bernhard (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - General correspondence, 1940 July 1 - 1945 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Correspondence concerning "Hoover Proposal", 1940 November 26-December 15 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Mendenhall, Thomas C. "Peace Aims in the War Collection" Yale Alumni Magazine, 1942 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 29a)
      - Pruden, Russell G. and Mendenhall, Thomas C. "The Yale Collection of War Literature," Yale University Library Gazette, 1942 July (Box 2, Folder 29a)
      - "Library Gathers Official, Personal Documents on World War. II," Yale Daily News, 1941 January 15 (Box 2, Folder 29a)
      - Correspondence with individuals re: War Collection
        - A - L, 1939-1948 (Box 2, Folder 29b)
        - M - Z, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 29c)
      - Correspondence with wartime organizations re: War Collection, 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Yale Library Project
        - Financial records and correspondence, chiefly between Thomas C. Mendenhall and Walter Pforzheimer, relating to a project to acquire materials in Europe and the Near East for the Yale University Library World War II Collection and for associated libraries. An operation secretly funded by the U.S. Office of Strategic Services as a military intelligence operation with Joseph T. Curtiss as agent.
        - Office of Strategic Services. Memoranda re: Yale Library Project (electrostatic copies), 1942-1945 (Box 2A, Folder 29e)
        - Correspondence, 1942-1948, 1977 (Box 2A, Folder 29f - 29l)
        - Guaranty Trust Company
          - Deposit book, account sheet and miscellaneous notes, 1942-1948 (Box 2A, Folder 29m)
          - Bank statements with cancelled checks, 1942-1948 (Box 2A, Folder 29n)
          - Checkbook for Yale and associated libraries, 1943-1948 (Box 2A, Folder 29o)
        - Accounts, 1943-1947 (Box 2A, Folder 29p)
    - Yale University. School of Medicine. Newspaper clippings, 1942 January - October (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Yale University. School of Nursing. Press releases, 1942 January 28, March 26 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Yale University. Secretary. Memoranda, 1941, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Yale Hospital Unit, Yale Medical Unit. Newspaper clippings, 1942 January - April (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - By Topic
    - Academic Program
      - Mendell, Clarence W. "Mr. Dooley on Acceleration", 1942 February (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Seymour, Charles. Announcements, 1942, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Applications, questionnaires, printed matter, 1942, 1943, 1946, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Newspaper clippings, press releases, reprints of articles, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Air Raid Precautions
      - Instructions for campus, arm bands, newspaper clippings, 1941-1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Yale University. Berkeley College. Memoranda, correspondence, 1941-1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Civil Defense
      - Registration card, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Certificate of recognition, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Conscientious objectors
      - Swift, Charles R. Statement, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - College Committee for Defense First, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 41)
        See also: box 2, folder 18
    - History
      - Seymour, Charles. "War's Impact on the Campus," New York Times, 1940 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1945 June (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - "War Years at Yale," chart showing progress of classes, 1945 August 2 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Memorabilia
      - Military passes, 1941, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Savings bonds, 1942-1944, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - War ration books, 1941-1943 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Postcard, "Bundles for Congress", undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - "In Wartime Yale" (song), undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Memorial and Peace Services
      - Programs for university assemblies, memorandum and taxts of speeches, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Programs for memorial services, 1946, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Military Service
      See also: box 5, folders 71-72
    - Post-War Planning
      - Yale University Post-War Planning Committee
        - Memoranda, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, 1941-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
        - Correspondence A - M, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 51)
        - Correspondence N - W, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 52)
        - Foreign Area Studies - Memoranda, correspondence, reports, drafts of reports, 1942-1944, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
        - Sub-Committee on Educational Planning - Memoranda, minutes, correspondnece, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Post-War Planning - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - "When You Come Back," Life, 1944 September 25 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1941, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Post-War Planning - Reports (typescripts)
      - Adler, J. Hans. "British and American Policies: A Problem and a Proposal", 1943 December 31 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Corbett, Percy E. "International Air Navigation and Anglo-American Relations", 1943 November 1 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Fox, William T.R. "Anglo-American Relations in the Post-War World", 1943 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - "Preliminary Report on the Proposed Organization for the New England Regional Planning Study", 1943 January 27 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Rowe, David Nelson. "China's Military Potential and the Enforcement of Peace", 1943 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Viner, Jacob. "Two Plans for International Monetary Stabilization", 1943 May (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - United Nations. Dumbarton Oaks Proposals, 1944 November - Dec, 1945 April 25, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Publicity
      - LaFarge, L. Bancel. "Yale Architects and National Defense," Yale Alumni Magazine, 1941 March 21 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - "Yale at War," Life, 1942 June (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Yale University News Bureau. Article sent to Yankee Magazine, [1943] (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Press releases, 1942 February 19, March 6 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Radio Broadcasts
      - "Yale Interprets the News"
        - 1944 November - 1945 March (Box 4, Folder 61)
        - 1945 April - May (Box 4, Folder 62)
        - 1945 June - August (Box 4, Folder 63)
        - undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - World Wide Broadcasting Foundation. First, Series
        - Scripts of broadcasts, 1943 December 10-31 (Box 4, Folder 65)
        - Notes on speakers, 1943 November 20, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
        - "Beyond Victory," scripts of radio broadcasts in collaboration with the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1943 August - September (Box 4, Folder 66)
        - Correspondence, 1943 September 17 - 1944 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - World Wide Broadcasting Foundation. Second Series
        - Schedules of speakers, notes, script of broadcast, 1944 February - March (Box 5, Folder 68)
        - Correspondence, 1943 December 3 - 1945 February 16, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Relief Organizations
      See also: box 2, folder 22
    - Selective Service
      See also: box 3, folders 47-49
    - Speakers
      - Symposium - "The Universities and National Defense," memorandum, press release, newspaper clippings, 1941 January - February (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Forum - "Leaders Wanted - Are Universities Meeting the Need?", list of speakers, 1941 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Yale Alumni Forum - "The United States and the Present European Conflict," texts of speeches, 1940 January 27 (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Browder, Earl. Speech at Yale under auspices of Yale Peace Council, 1939 November 28 (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - Dill, Sir John. Text of speech at Yale. Text of remarks of reply by George C. Marshall, 1944 February 14 (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Dobbie, William. Poster, 1945 May 24 (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Lindbergh, Charles A. Typewritten MS of speech at Yale under auspices of America First Committee, 1940 October 30 (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Luce, Clare (Boothe). TMS of "Credo delivered at Yale", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 77a)
      - Luce, Henry R. "The American Century," typewritten MS, [1941] (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Mann, Erika. Typewritten MS of speech, 1940 December 10 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Maurer, Oscar E. "The Church's Task in Time of War," typewritten MS of sermon, 1941 December 14 (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Student Activities
      - International Student Service. Press releases, newspaper clippings, 1939 16 - 1941 December 1 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Yale Daily News war polls - Newspaper clippings, 1939 October 4 - 1941 November 5 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Newspaper clippings - General, 1939-1946 (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - Newspaper clippings - Foreign fronts, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - Newspaper clippings - Latin America, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - War Casualties
      - Proposed plans for memorials for Yale student, undated (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Gosselin, Edward Webb. Newspaper clipping, 1942 February 24 (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Green, John McKinley. Printed matter and correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1944 April - October (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - 1944 October - 1945 March (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - 1945 March - June (Box 6A, Folder 89)
- WAR ACTIVITIES, 1939-1950, undated; Series II; 0.75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  On Campus is arranged alphabetically by branch of the armed forces. Abroad is arranged alphabetically by country. Articles, Reports, Clippings and Writings by Yale Men is arranged alphabetically by author. Newspaper clippings are filed at the end of the section.
  - On Campus
    - Air Force - Songs, 1943, 1944, undated (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Army. Civil Affairs Training School-Certificate of completion, 1944 April 22 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Army Service Forces. Army Specialized Training Division- Memoranda, printed matter, 1943 April - 1944 Mar, undated (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Army Navy College Training Program-Printed matter, 1943 Apr, undated (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Engineering Defense Training Program-Reports, press releases, newspaper clippings, 1941-1942, undated (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Enlisted Reserve Corps - Memoranda, 1942 August 31, undated (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Military Training Camps Association-Memorandum, newspaper article, 1940 May 23, undated (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Naval aviation, Army aviation - Pamphlet, press releases, newspaper clippings, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 97)
    - Navy - Naval Reserve and Navy V-1 pamphlets, 1941, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - Navy - Handbooks: Marshall Islands, Survival on Land and Sea, 1943, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Navy College Training Program V-12
      - Applications, bulletins, 1943, 1944, undated (Box 7, Folder 100)
      - Curricula, course schedules, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - Memoranda, 1943-1946, undated (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - War Department
      - Technical Manual. Emergency Food Plants and Poisonous Plants of the Islands of the Pacific, 1943 April 15 (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - Drafts of reports and articles, correspondence, 1942-1943, undated (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - War and Navy Departments. A Pocket Guide to New Guinea and the Solomons, undated (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Abroad
    - China. "Yale Inn" at Changsha, 1945 September 1 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - India. Yale-Harvard Club, 1944 April 12 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Morocco. Yale University Club, 1943 July 31 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Articles, Reports, Clippings and Writings by Yale Men
    - Adams, Alexander B. "They Sit in Judgment," Hartford Courant, 1940 March 3 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Borchard, Edwin M. "Misreading History?", letter to the editor, New York Herald Times, 1941 September 28 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Gardner, W.H. Y.1916. "Yale and Naval Aviation", undated (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Hemingway, Samuel Burdett. Notes about Berkeley College men in the war, 1944 December 7, undated (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Lord, William Y.1945. "The Battle for Thier du Mont Ridge", undated (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1939-1943 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Tyler, Parker. "From Seattle to Ie Shima with the 413th Fighter Group", 1945 (Box 8, Folder 115)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1940-1946, undated; Series III; 1.25 linear feet (2 boxes)